the time has finally come to decorate
终于到了装饰的时候了
our delicious looking donut with some
我们的甜甜圈看起来很好吃
sprinkles so the feature we need for
所以我们需要的功能
that is called geometry nodes and you
这被称为几何体节点 而您
can access it by going to the top of
可以通过转到
your screen if you don't see it just
你的屏幕 如果你看不到它
middle Mouse drag across and you'll see
鼠标中键拖过来 你就会看到
the tab geometry nodes ohoo so it's
标签几何体节点 所以它是
adjusted your screen layout don't get
调整了您的屏幕布局 不会
disorientated your Don note is still
迷失方向的你的唐笔记还在
there this screen on the left here it's
左边的屏幕在这里 它是
called the spreadsheet never needed it
称为电子表格 从来不需要它
touch on would never will um so we can
触摸永远不会 嗯 所以我们可以
just close that right click join areas
只需关闭右击连接区域即可
and then just collapse it into it okay
然后把它折叠起来 好吗？
so with your icing selected click the
因此选择您的糖霜后 请单击
new button so welcome to the world of
新按钮欢迎来到世界
geometry nodes so geometry nodes is
几何体节点 因此几何体节点是
actually a modifier so when we hit new
实际上是修饰语 所以当我们点击新的
there we've added in a modifier called
在这里 我们添加了一个修饰符 称为
geometry nodes and what the modifier is
几何体节点和修改器是什么
doing is whatever we want it to okay so
做任何我们想做的事 好吗
what this this section down here is this
下面这一段是什么？
is a node based system and it looks
是一个基于节点的系统 它看起来
familiar right you got boxes with little
熟悉吧 你得到的盒子里有很少
Lin lines and it's the exact same type
林的线条和它是一模一样的
of system that was used in our materials
在我们的材料中使用的系统
right but it's a completely different
是的 但这是完全不同的
system okay so the same nodes will not
系统正常 因此相同的节点不会
be referenced um between the completely
被引用的那个完全在
different systems so the way this works
不同的系统 所以这是一种工作方式
is our mesh that we've got here of our
我们这里的网状结构是我们的
icing is what is being represented on
结冰就是在上面表现出来的
the left hand side with your input it's
左手边有你的输入
then taking that mesh and it's feeding
然后取下网状物 它就会进食
it all the way to the right and it's
它一直往右走 它是
going to spit out whatever is in your
会把你肚子里的东西都吐出来
group output So currently nothing has
组输出 因此当前没有
changed because there's nothing between
改变是因为两者之间没有什么
those points
那几点
but if I was for example don't follow me
但如果我是 那就别跟着我
but just as an example if I was to add a
但仅作为一个示例 如果我要添加一个
set position node drop this in here and
设置位置节点将此放入此处 然后
then change the position of the icing
然后改变结冰的位置
along the Zed axis you can see it's
沿着ZED轴你可以看到它
raised it okay now the mesh if I go into
把它举起来 好的 如果我进入
edit mode is still there the mesh has
编辑模式仍在网格中
not changed so we're not actually moving
没有改变 所以我们实际上不会移动
the object this is just happening after
这件事发生后的物体
the fact via a modifier okay now
通过修饰语的事实现在好了
obviously this would be a rather
显然 这将是一个相当大的
pointless use for geometry nodes to move
将几何体节点用于移动毫无意义
move it cuz you could just move it um
移动它 因为你只需移动它
but as an example let's say I don't know
但举个例子 我不知道
you had a scene where lots of objects
你有一个场景 里面有很多物体
some of them are raised some of them are
他们中的一些人被抚养长大 一些人是
not and you wanted to quickly change
不是的 你想要迅速改变
them what you could do with geometry
你可以对几何学做些什么
nodes in this case you could actually
节点在本例中 您实际上可以
expose this offset value by dragging it
通过拖动来显示此偏移值
to the left over here and when you do
在这里的左边 当你这样做的时候
that you can see it's now appeared over
你可以看到它现在已经出现在
here in our modifier stack what that
在我们的修改器堆栈中
means is whenever I'm in another part of
意思是每当我在另一部分的时候
B of blender say I'm like building stuff
搅拌机的B说我喜欢建筑材料
and I'm like oh yeah I need to quickly
我就想 哦 是的 我需要快点
you know change the the height of that
你知道改变它的高度
icing I've got it there whenever I need
当我需要的时候 我就会把它放在那里
to so essentially this system enables
因此 该系统基本上能够实现
you to build your own tool that does
您需要构建自己的工具来完成
something that you want it to do in a
你想让它在一个
really flexible way so it's really
非常灵活的方式 所以它真的
powerful um and before geometry nodes I
强大的Um和之前的几何体节点i
mean blender was kind of limited in what
卑鄙的搅拌机在什么方面受到了限制
you can do but I'll throw some examples
你可以这样做 但我会举几个例子
here but in the last 2 years since it's
在这里 但在过去的两年里
uh been in blender people have done some
呃 在搅拌机里 人们已经做了一些
wild stuff with it um and most of this
狂野的东西 嗯 还有这个的大部分
stuff really was just not part possible
有些事情真的是不可能的
in blender before without doing custom
在搅拌机中使用之前不进行定制
scripting so it's really opened up the
编写脚本 因此它真正打开了
doors so it is a very different system
所以这是一个非常不同的系统
like it's a different way of working um
就像这是一种不同的工作方式
than you know just Hands-On in 3D but
比你知道的在3D中动手更多 但是
it's a really flexible really valuable
它非常灵活 非常有价值
um system so any time spent learning
UM系统 所以花在学习上的任何时间
geometry nodes I think is time well
几何节点我认为是时间的好
spent so we want to do sprinkles and to
花掉了 所以我们想要做洒水和
do that we need to first of all scatter
要做到这一点 我们首先需要分散
some points onto our mesh so to do that
一些点到我们的网格上 这样做
hit shift a a for ADD and then we're
按下Shift a进行添加 然后我们将
looking for Point distribute points on
在以下位置查找点分布点
faces okay and then it's just put uh
脸没问题 然后就是把呃
sorry it's going to put you in a
抱歉 这会让你陷入
placement State and if you just Mouse
放置状态和如果您只使用鼠标
over that line there till it lights up
越过那条线 直到它亮起来
if you click it's going to automatically
如果你点击 它会自动转到
connect it for you and now you can see
为您连接它 现在您可以看到
we've got points on our icing and our
我们在我们的糖衣和我们的
density value great but you might notice
密度值很好 但您可能会注意到
the icing has actually disappeared ooh
糖霜其实已经消失了哦
now the reason for that is we've told it
现在的原因是我们已经说过了
okay give us take that icing object and
好的 把那个结冰的东西给我们
convert it into points and then just
把它转换成点 然后
give us the points back okay so what we
把分数还给我们 好的 那我们怎么办
need to do is say yes we want the points
需要做的就是说是的 我们想要积分
but we also want the original mesh so we
但是我们也想要原始的网格 所以我们
can do that by adding in a node that you
可以通过添加您要添加的节点来完成此操作
use all the time which is shift a
使用所有的时间 也就是轮班
geometry join geometry so you'll find
几何图形连接几何图形 这样您就会发现
this node in probably any geometry noes
此节点可能在任何几何图形中都不存在
tutorial very versatile so drop it in
教程非常多才多艺 所以把它放进去
here after the points and you'll notice
在积分之后 你会注意到
this input here is a different shape so
此处的输入是不同的形状 因此
normally inputs are circles or you know
通常情况下 输入是圆形的 或者你知道
triangles or whatnot this one is a long
三角形或诸如此类的东西这一个是长的
an elongated shape to signify that it
一个细长的形状 表示它
can accept multiple inputs so one likee
可以接受多个输入 这样一个人就可以
these where you can only accept one this
在这些地方 你只能接受一个这个
can accept many so what we need to do is
可以接受很多人 所以我们需要做的是
take the output of our original mesh and
以原始网格的输出为例
then feed it over to here and now we
然后把它送到这里 现在我们
have both the original mesh and we have
既有原始网格 又有
our points and they're being combined
我们的观点和他们正在结合起来
together and then put into our output
然后放到我们的输出中
okay very cool awesome all right so if
好的 非常酷 太棒了 好的 如果
we were to give this a render right now
我们本打算现在就给这个做个渲染
you would actually see nothing because
你实际上什么也看不到 因为
these points don't physically exist they
这些点在物理上并不存在
just exist in the 3D space if we want
如果我们想要的话就存在于3D空间
them to show up in the render we have to
要在渲染中显示它们 我们必须
tell it what do you want to render them
告诉它您希望呈现什么内容
as so for that we need to add an object
因此 我们需要添加一个对象
to be our sprinkle so your sprinkle
成为我们的花洒所以你的花洒
could be whatever you want uh we're
可以是你想要的任何东西 呃 我们
actually going to make two different
实际上会让两个不同的人
types of sprinkles in this uh donut
这个呃甜甜圈里撒的东西的种类
Series so we're going to start though
系列 所以我们将从
with a very simple one just a round ball
一个非常简单的球 就是一个圆球
so uh just like you would add another
所以 呃 就像你会添加另一个
object normally shift a and then go mesh
对象通常先移动a 然后移动网格
and then go UV sphere now this sphere is
然后转到UV球体现在这个球体是
going to be referenced for every single
将会被引用到每一个
sprinkle okay so we want to go uh as low
好的 所以我们想要最低的
res as we can get away with uh so I'm
因为我们可以逃脱惩罚 所以我
going to go with a 12 segments and then
会有12个片段 然后
eight Rings if you're on a really slow
如果你真的开得很慢 那就是八环
computer and you think this is really
计算机 你认为这真的是
going to suffer later on um you could go
以后会受苦的 嗯 你可以去
even lower but I don't want to go too
更低 但我不想走得太远
low because otherwise we're going to see
很低 因为否则我们会看到
that Jagged Edge cuz it's a rounded form
那个锯齿状的边缘 因为它是圆形的
so I don't want to go too much lower
所以我不想降得太低
than that uh but I do want to adjust the
呃 但是我确实想调整一下
scale because obviously this needs to be
扩展 因为显然这需要
a tiny little sprinkle so let's go
洒了一小点 我们走吧
0.1 okay awesome all right now with our
0.1好的 太棒了 现在我们的
icing selected again you'll notice by
再次选择结冰 您会注意到
the way that if you click another object
如果你点击另一个物体
you don't see your nose because it's
你看不到你的鼻子 因为它是
only going to show you the active
我只会向你展示活动的
objects geometry nodes so if you want
对象几何体节点 因此如果需要
the nodes to just be there no matter
节点就在那里 无论如何
what if you click the pin button there
如果你点击那里的大头针按钮会怎么样
that means no matter what is selected
这意味着无论选择什么
it's only going to be showing you this
它只会向你展示这个
objects uh the one that we pinned uh
物体呢 我们钉住的那个 呃
geometry noes okay all right so to
几何问题 好的 好的 所以
reference we need to reference that
引用我们需要引用的内容
little sphere that we've just created in
我们刚刚在其中创建的小球体
our geometry node system and you can do
我们的几何节点系统和您可以做的
it very easily just by dragging down
只需将其拖放即可轻松实现
from your outliner up here just dragging
从你的大纲图上拖到这里
it down into your geometry nodes and
它深入到您的几何体节点中
dropping it okay so now let's just
别说了 好吧 现在我们就
create some room here make a little bit
在这里腾出一些空间来做一点
of
的
space okay and what I need to do is add
空间好的 我需要做的是添加
another node to reference this object
引用此对象的另一个节点
and the node is shift a instances
且该节点是移位一个实例
instances on points the top one okay and
点上的实例顶部的实例正常 并且
then I want to drop it in here between
然后我想把它放在中间的地方
distribute points on faces and my join
在面和我的连接上分布点
geometry so drop it in right there till
几何 所以把它放在那里 直到
it lights up now the points have
它现在亮起来了 点数已经
disappeared because we're now saying
消失是因为我们现在说
replace those points with whatever is in
用中的任何内容替换这些点
that instance input so I'm going to take
该实例输入 所以我将使用
my geometry from my object info and drag
我的几何体从我的对象信息和拖动
it into the instance and look at that we
把它放到实例中 然后看看我们
have got our spheres appearing all over
我们的球体到处都是
it and if I increase the density we've
如果我增加我们的密度
got sprinkles and if I do a render it
得到了散布 如果我渲染它
will actually display doesn't look very
实际上看起来并不是很好
good hey but it does work which is the
好的 嘿 但它确实起作用了 这是
uh the main thing right now okay so uh
呃 现在最重要的是好的 所以 呃
first things first you'll notice that as
首先 你会注意到
we increase the density first problem is
我们增加密度的第一个问题是
that uh they're crowding each other they
呃 他们互相挤在一起
are straight up overlapping each other
是直接相互重叠的
with no respect for its fellow sprinkle
不尊重它的同伴洒水
right because it's just a random
对 因为这只是一个随机的
distribution so we can change that by
分发 因此我们可以通过以下方式改变
going here in our distribute points on
在我们的分发点上
faces change it from random distri dist
面孔将它从随机分布改变为
distribution to Pon disc distribution
分布到PON圆盘分布
Pon what a name um so it's changed uh
什么名字 嗯 所以它变了 嗯
but that's just because it's changed
但那只是因为它已经改变了
your density Max so just increase it
您的密度最大值 所以只需增加它
again um with this pron dis uh
再一次 嗯 用这首歌
distribution you get this extra value
分配 您将获得额外的价值
here distance Min so now if we can uh
这里距离Min所以现在如果我们可以呃
set a low value we can start to delete
设置一个我们可以开始删除的较低值
it's it's almost like each one of those
它几乎就像是每一个
points is going to have a little radius
点将会有一个小半径
around it and if it detects a point
如果它检测到一个点
within that radius it's going to delete
在该半径内 它将删除
it so um we just need to increase it
所以 嗯 我们只需要增加
slowly very very slowly until we can't
慢慢地直到我们不能
see them intersecting anymore um to
看到他们再相交了 嗯 到
about there
关于那里
honestly if you go too high like if you
老实说 如果你走得太高 就像你
really wanted to make sure they weren't
我真的很想确保他们不会
touching you go really high but it
触摸你真的很高 但它
starts to look like too evenly spaced
开始看起来太均匀了
you know like yeah it's it's not
你知道 是的 这不是
actually registering the other object
实际上正在注册另一个对象
it's like it's just doing this little
就像它只是在做这个小小的
radius thing which just happens to be
半径的问题 恰好是
perfect for a ball-shaped object but
非常适合球状物体 但
it's not like an advanced like it's
它不像是高级的 而是
going to try to fill in all the gaps for
我要试着填补所有的空白
you um so yeah just kind of I usually
你 嗯 是啊 只是我通常
set it to like a little bit of clipping
把它设置成有点像剪裁
is okay but I don't want there to be uh
很好 但我不想有 呃
too much um but let's go yeah something
太多了 嗯 但我们走吧 是的 有些东西
I don't know something like that we'll
我不知道这样的事情 我们会
actually adjust this later on I'm just
实际上以后再调整这个 我只是
doing it just for this this point all
这么做就是为了这一点
right a much bigger problem if I hit
对 如果我撞到了一个更大的问题
control tab to go full screen here if I
如果我执行以下操作 控制选项卡将在此处全屏
look at uh at my mesh I've got sprinkles
看 呃 看我的网眼 我有水珠
everywhere and in fact I've actually got
无处不在 事实上我有
sprinkles underneath the icing and
洒在糖衣下面
that's not good because it's actually
这不太好 因为它实际上
going to put that in the render even
我会把它放到渲染中
though you won't see it your computer is
尽管你看不到它 但你的电脑
going to use resources to render little
将使用资源呈现很少的内容
individual balls underneath the icing
糖衣下的单个球
which is not what we want obviously so
这显然不是我们想要的 所以
going back here what we need to do to
回到这里 我们需要做的是
fix this is we need to do weight
解决这个问题是我们需要做重量练习
painting okay it's not texture painting
绘画好的 这不是纹理绘画
it's a special thing called weight
这是一种特殊的东西 叫做重量
painting So with your icing selected if
如果选择了糖霜 则可以进行绘制
you go from your object mode you'll see
你离开你的对象模式 你会看到
one there called weight paint now your
有一种叫重量油漆 现在是你的
mesh will become blue and weight paint
网格将变为蓝色 并增加颜色权重
is actually referenced in multiple parts
实际上是在多个部分引用的
of blender like if you're doing rigging
搅拌机 就像你在做索具
and animation you would use weight
和动画 你会使用权重
painting a lot during the rigging step
在索具步骤中进行大量涂装
to assign values to certain bones
为某些骨骼指定值
essentially what it's doing is it's
从本质上讲 它的作用是
allowing you to paint a value between
允许您在以下范围内绘制值
zero and one onto any part of the mesh
0和1到网格的任何部分
and then reference that however you want
然后以你想要的方式引用它
so we can then reference that weight
这样我们就可以参考那个重量
paint mask in our geometry nodes and use
在几何体节点中绘制遮罩并使用
this almost as well exactly as a mask
这几乎和面具一样好
for our uh
为了我们的这个
sprinkles so if we just do uh just do
所以如果我们只是做 呃 就做
some paint right here on it you'll see
上面有一些油漆 你会看到的
that we have some colors right now these
我们现在有一些颜色
colors aren't going to appear in the red
颜色不会出现在红色中
it's just for you to visualize those
只是让你想象一下那些
values uh the blue value means a zero a
值呃 蓝色的值表示零a
value of zero and the red value is a
值为零 而红色值是一个
zero of one I believe actually in maybe
我实际上相信的可能是零个一
not the next version of blender but
不是下一个版本的搅拌机 而是
maybe the version I don't know but
可能是我不知道的版本 但是
they're planning to change the colors of
他们正计划改变颜色
this so depending on the value on how
这取决于价值如何
late watching this you are your colors
深夜看这个 你是你的颜色
might be different here but it should be
在这里可能不同 但应该是不同的
the same essentially you should have a
本质上相同的 你应该有一个
brush of one um and you should be able
刷一刷嗯 你应该可以
to paint from zero which would give a
从零开始绘制 这将产生一个
blue value in this case to a value of
在本例中 蓝色值设置为
one so whatever is one whatever is red
一个 所以不管是什么 红色是什么
is where our sprinkles will go but
是我们的花洒的去处 但是
you'll notice that this is not having
你会注意到 这并不是
any effect okay so we need to reference
任何效果都可以 所以我们需要参考
it now that weight paint that we just
它现在的重量油漆 我们刚刚
did is actually if we go to our data tab
实际上是如果我们转到数据选项卡
here it's actually a Vertex group okay
这实际上是一个顶点群 好的
so that's where that paint went so you
所以那是油漆的去处 所以你
could actually create multiple weight
实际上可以创建多个权重
paint types just by like creating them
只需像创建类型一样绘制类型
here um but we've just created one and
在这里 嗯 但我们刚刚创建了一个
it's added one here for us so we can
它在这里为我们增加了一个 所以我们可以
give it a name by double clicking it and
通过双击它为其命名 然后
let's call it sprinkle mosque okay in
我们把它叫做喷洒清真寺好吗？
fact it's a is it a Mosk it's more of a
事实上 它是一个穆斯林吗？它更像是一个
density sprinkle density I guess cuz
密度洒水密度我猜是因为
it's not a masking out anyway all right
不管怎么说 这不是掩饰 好吧
sprinkle density um okay and where I
洒上密度 嗯 好的 我在哪里
want to reference this in my geometry
想要在我的几何图形中引用它
node stack is in the distribute points
节点堆栈位于分布点中
on faces there is one value here called
在面孔上 有一个值叫做
density factor which we got when we use
我们在使用时得到的密度系数
the presson dis thing and this is just a
普雷森的事 这只是一个
value of 0 to one very convenient so if
值从0到1非常方便 因此如果
I drag out from here and then release I
我从这里拖出来 然后释放我
can add in a new node and it'll just
可以添加一个新节点 然后它就会
automatically connect it and the node
自动将其与节点连接
that you're looking for is called the
你要找的东西被称为
named attribute don't feel bad if you're
命名属性如果您是
like well how would I know that it's
就像我怎么知道这是
called the named attribute cuz it's
之所以称为命名属性 是因为它
called vertex groups over here you think
在这里称为顶点群 你认为
like okay I'm going to type in vertex
比如 好的 我要输入顶点
group but it's an attribute but it's one
组 但它是一个属性 但它是一个
of many attributes and geometry nodes
包含多个属性和几何体节点
can do many things so it's just called
可以做很多事情 所以就叫它
the named attribute so anyways all right
命名属性所以不管怎样 好吧
so underneath name we're just going to
所以在名字下面 我们只需
click that box you'll get a pop up or
点击该框 您将看到一个弹出窗口 或者
pop down and you looking for sprinkle
向下弹出 你在寻找洒水
density and there it is haha so now
密度 就在那里 哈哈 所以现在
going back into weight paint mode we can
回到权重绘制模式 我们可以
act like an artist and put the sprinkles
表现得像个艺术家 把花洒
wherever we want sprinkles on our donut
只要我们想在甜甜圈上撒点水
which is really cool um so so sprinkles
这真的很酷 嗯 所以撒了
are typically they're like on a plate
它们通常就像放在盘子里一样
and then the wet donut with icing on it
然后是加了糖衣的湿甜甜圈
is just like dabbed onto it so you get
就像是轻拍它 这样你就可以
like a heavy amount of sprinkles right
就像大量的洒水 对吗？
on the top like that and then less
像这样放在顶端 然后再少一些
around the sides um and then I usually
在两边 嗯 然后我通常
do like a few like dabs like
做一些喜欢的 喜欢的 喜欢的
this just for some variance and then
这只是为了一些差异 然后
also if you hold down control that will
另外 如果你按住Ctrl键 就会
do a so the the weight that's being
做一件事 所以它的重量是
painted is one but if I hold down
画的是一个 但如果我按住
control it's going to do a negative
控制它会产生负面影响
value and I can adjust my strength there
价值 我可以在那里调整我的力量
as well and I can just do some negative
同样 我也可以做一些负面的
uh paints across it maybe a couple here
呃 画在上面 也许这里有几个
as
AS
well and I'm trying to deliberately make
嗯 我正试着故意让
it look choppy because I find that if
它看起来起伏不定 因为我发现如果
you make it look too like uniform then
你让它看起来太像制服了
it just looks very boring and artificial
只是看起来很无聊 很做作
um because the real world would have
嗯 因为现实世界会有
more sprinkles collecting in certain
一定会有更多的雨点聚集
areas than others right maybe it's just
比其他地区更好的地方 也许只是
like wetter on that part right so more
就像更湿的那一部分 所以更多
would stick to it um or more force was
会坚持下去 嗯 或者更多的力量是
put on that part of the plate as the
放在盘子的那一部分作为
doughnut was dabbed into it right you
甜甜圈是沾在里面的 对吧？
just kind of have to think of this stuff
我就是得想想这些东西
because uh in the digital world it's far
因为 呃 在数字世界里 它远远
too easy to make something that looks um
做一些看起来呃很容易的东西
predictable and boring and we don't want
可预见的和乏味的 我们不想
that but there we go something like that
但我们要做的就是这样
um and you could obviously finesse it
嗯 你显然可以巧妙地利用它
and make it better than what it is but
让它变得更好 但
that's uh that's what we got uh you'll
这是 呃 这就是我们的 呃 你会
notice each of these spheres have a very
请注意 每个球体都有一个非常
Jagged looking shape and that's because
参差不齐的形状 那是因为
the sphere itself down here oh I don't
这里的球体本身 哦 我不知道
think I mentioned this if you want to
如果你想的话我想我提过这个
quickly Zoom to an object without having
快速缩放到对象 而不需要
to find it and pan around number pad
找到它并在数字键盘周围平移
period key probably should have
期间密钥可能应该具有
mentioned that before um but we've only
以前也提到过 但是我们只是
haven't really needed it because we have
并不是真的需要它 因为我们有
not work with that many objects but
不是使用那么多对象 但
that'll Focus to that object if you're
它会聚焦到该对象 如果您
on a laptop by the way if you hold down
顺便说一下 在笔记本电脑上 如果你按住
the Tia key that'll bring up this
Tia的钥匙会带来这个
section here and then you've got view
这里的部分 然后你就可以看到
selected right there so tiller is that
就在那里被选中 所以分耕者是
key underneath your uh Escape key but
钥匙在你的呃Escape钥匙下面 但是
anyways so this is what our sphere looks
不管怎么说 这就是我们的球体
like so right click shade smooth and now
就像这样 用鼠标右键点击阴影平滑 现在
all those sprinkles have a shade smooth
所有这些洒水都有一种色调光滑
haha very nice all right now let me just
哈哈 非常好 好了 现在让我
show you a quick uh little issue that
给你看一个快速的呃小问题
you might run into if you were to uh
如果你去呃你可能会碰到
duplicate your donut and uh create two
复制你的甜甜圈 呃 创造两个
and then on the second donut you're like
然后在第二个甜甜圈上你就像
hey I want to have uh some spice in my
嘿 我想在我的
scene I don't want to have the exact
场景我不想有确切的
same count of sprinkles across both
两种情况下洒水的数量相同
Donuts let's give a a different value to
甜甜圈 让我们给一个不同的值
this one over here well you can see that
这个在这里 你可以看到那个
they are now sharing the same value
它们现在共享着相同的价值
because this node group here is being
因为这里的这个节点组是
linked across both objects um but if you
跨两个对象链接 嗯 但如果
wanted I mean you could like you know
想要我的意思是你可以像你知道的那样
make it its own single object so they're
让它成为自己的单一对象 这样他们就可以
not linked but if you wanted everything
没有链接 但如果你想要一切
else to to remain the same so that let's
否则就会保持不变 让我们
say you you know change the sprinkle at
说你 你知道的 换个点缀
some point that's preserved across it
一些被保留下来的点
but that one value you want to be
但你想要的那个价值
different across multiple objects you
不同于您的多个对象
can expose it so just like what I did at
可以把它曝光 就像我
the start if I drag out from the value I
从值I拖出的开始If
want to expose and then I put it up to
想要曝光 然后我把它放在
here in my group input the empty slot if
在我的组中 输入空位 如果
I just release it it's now disappeared
我只是释放它 它现在已经消失了
the value's disappeared from here and
它的价值从这里消失了
it's now appeared in my modifier stack
它现在出现在我的修改器堆栈中
over here and now I can put in a
在这里 现在我可以放一个
different value so this has now got a
不同的值 所以它现在有一个
value of 2,000 and this one is 500 so
价值2,000美元 这个是500美元
essentially by dragging it out and
基本上是把它拖出来 然后
exposing it it's essentially removing
把它暴露出来 基本上是在移除
the value from this uh node setup and
这个呃节点设置的值和
saying this is its own separate thing
说这是它自己的事情
which is independent per object um and
其对于每个对象um是独立的并且
it has a two birds uh one stone kind of
它有两只鸟 呃 一块石头之类的
effect that it makes it more accessible
它的效果是使它更容易访问
so in a completely different part of
所以在一个完全不同的部分
blender I'm working on my scene and I'm
搅拌机我在拍我的场景 我
just very quickly giving different
很快就会给出不同的
sprinkle amounts to different Donuts
洒上的甜甜圈就是不同的
right like a mad man right no one can
就像疯子一样 没人能做到
stop me um but yeah very cool and uh
让我停下来 嗯 但是的 非常酷 嗯
that's now exposed oh the other thing we
现在曝光了 哦 还有一件事 我们
probably want to do though with that uh
可能想要这样做 呃
this group input here is I want to give
这里的这个组输入是我想要给出的
it a different name because density Max
它有一个不同的名字 因为密度最大
you know not really that useful I can
你知道我真的没什么用处
call it sprinkle density right so now
现在就称它为洒水密度吧
it's like a fully customized little node
它就像一个完全定制的小节点
group that I could drop on any object I
我可以放在任何对象上的组
could be building a car in the future
可能是在未来制造一辆汽车
and I'm like it it needs sprinkles and I
我喜欢它 它需要洒水 而我
can just drop this on and I've got a
只要把这个放在上面 我就会有一个
Sprinkle density value for my car right
为我的汽车右侧散布密度值
so you can see how geometry nodes you
这样您就可以看到几何体节点是如何
can build something really customized
我可以构建一些真正定制的东西
for what you want and then it's just
为了你想要的 然后就是
readily accessible um every time you
随时可访问的嗯 每次您
need to use it awesome now one issue
现在需要使用它很棒的一个问题
that I will show you with this and
我会用这个展示给你们看
actually it's not specific to Geometry
实际上 它并不是专门针对几何的
noes but this entire time for all these
不 但这整个时间都是为了这些
videos
视频
we've been building a dut which is too
我们一直在建造一座DUT
big so if you hit n in your properties
很大 所以如果你在你的属性中点击了n
oh that's the polygon thing uh you can
哦 那是多边形的东西 呃 你可以
see the size the dimensions of your dut
看看你的DUT的尺寸
is 1.2x 1.2 M which uh for Americans oh
是1.2x1.2M 呃 对美国人来说哦
actually yeah you can change it you
实际上 是的 你可以改变它 你
could change your units to the wacky
可以把你的单位换成古怪的
Imperial one yeah four feet right okay
帝国一号 对 四英尺 好的
um which is way too big okay now why
嗯 这太大了 好吧 为什么
does it matter right because like okay
这有关系吗 因为就像好的
if you're looking at this this how are
如果你在看这个 这是怎么回事
you to actually know that this is 1.2 M
你要知道这是1.2M
rather than the regular size zut it
而不是常规尺寸的ZUT
doesn't actually matter yet but when we
其实还不重要 但当我们
get to like rendering with depth of
喜欢使用深度的渲染
field or maybe you want to import other
字段或您可能想要导入其他
objects from other scenes having a value
来自其他场景的对象具有值
that is actually true to the object will
这实际上是对对象的真实意志
save you so much time and it'll also
为你节省了这么多时间 而且它还
make it so that your camera settings Etc
让你的相机设置等
are actually correct so that bit is uh
实际上是正确的 所以那个比特是呃
is very important so essentially we
是非常重要的 所以基本上我们
should resize this and really a real
应该调整这个的大小 真正的
donor is about 12 CM which is exactly
供体大约12厘米 这恰好是
1/10th of what we've got right here so
是我们这里的十分之一 所以
if we select everything in the entire
如果我们选择整个
scene which you can do by just hitting a
场景 你只需点击一个
a for everything I don't know a for all
A代表我不知道的一切 A代表所有人
yeah that makes more sense okay uh then
是的 那就更有意义了 好吧 呃 那么
if we hit s to scale okay we're now in a
如果我们击中S 好的 我们现在是在一个
scale oh actually okay well now it's
比例尺哦 实际上 好的 现在它是
going to scale it and the plane is going
要把它缩成比例 飞机就会飞起来
to be off the ground hm okay all right
离开地面 嗯好的 好的
well let's not let's not scale the lamp
好了 让我们不要不刻度台灯
and the the camera so everything else
还有摄像机 所以其他的一切
selecting the donut the lamp sorry the
选择甜甜圈灯对不起
donut the plane and the sphere then s
圆环平面和球体然后S
and then I want to scale it by exactly
然后我想精确地按比例进行调整
10% now how could I do that if you look
10%现在我怎么能做到如果你看起来
in the top leftand Corner you've got uh
在左上角 你有呃
the values there and if I if I went to
那里的价值观 如果我去
0.1 then it would be exactly a tenth of
0.1那么正好是十分之一
what it was but how can I get it exactly
它是什么 但我怎么才能准确地得到它呢
at 0.1 well uh two things one if you
在0.1 嗯 有两件事 一是如果你
hold down control when you're moving any
移动时按住Ctrl
value in blender it'll move it in
价值在搅拌机中 它会将其移入
increments which in this case is 0.1 but
增量 在本例中为0.1 但
you can also actually just type in the
实际上 您也可以只键入
exact value you want point one and hit
准确的价值 你想要的第一点和命中
enter and now if we look at the size of
进入 现在如果我们看一下
our donut Click N Hit N uh you can see
我们的甜甜圈点击N点击N呃你可以看到
it's
它是
.12 M or centim you know anyway um and
.12米或厘米 你知道的 不管怎样 嗯和
that's great but there is a problem uh
太好了 但是有个问题 嗯
what you might notice I mean there's not
你可能会注意到 我的意思是没有
a problem now but when you change the
现在是个问题 但当您更改
scale or the rotation of object actually
对象的实际比例或旋转
it's uh it's not it's only changed its
它呃它不是它只是改变了它的
uh what do you call it its local scale
呃 你叫它什么地方规模？
it hasn't actually applied it on a
它实际上还没有将其应用于
global level yet so the sprinkle here
全球水平 所以这里的散布
and the dut have actually got a like
而DUT实际上有一个类似的
pretend value this scale is set at 0 2
假设值此比例设置为0 2
and it's almost like it's saying to the
这几乎就像是在对
scene that's not its real scale it's
那个场景不是它的真实规模 它是
just been faked to be that size yet it
只是被伪装成那样大小 但它
needs to be applied if you want to like
如果您想要
confirm really that this is the true
确认这是真的
scale of rotation of the thing and you
物体和你的旋转比例
do that by selecting the things and then
要做到这一点 可以选择一些东西 然后
hitting contr a and then applying
点击Contra 然后应用
scale okay so now we've done that we can
好的 现在我们已经做到了 我们可以
see something's changed so our donut
看到一些东西改变了 所以我们的甜甜圈
here with the sprinkles has now
在这里洒满了水 现在
massively changed its uh density count
大量改变了它的呃密度计数
and the reason for this is that if we go
这么做的原因是如果我们
geometry nodes again let's zoom in here
几何体结点再次让我们放大这里
let's look at it with
让我们一起来看看
this this density this sprinkle density
这个密度这个洒下的密度
is actually not the count of sprinkles
实际上并不是洒水的数量
at all it's the density in relation to
这完全是与密度有关的
the whole scene and the way I think of
整个场景和我想到的方式
it is like um uh okay it's a weird
这就像 嗯 好的 这是一种奇怪的
visualization but if you've got a car
但如果你有一辆车
and it's driving along a highway right a
它正沿着高速公路向右行驶
certain amount of bugs are going to hit
一定数量的虫子将会攻击
the windshield okay but and the bugs
挡风玻璃没问题 但还有虫子
could be defined by here but the smaller
可以用这里来定义 但更小的
the object is right you could have the
对象是对的 你可以拥有
same amount of bugs going across the
相同数量的错误在整个
highway but if it was like a tiny
高速公路 但如果它像一个小的
Matchbox car there's going to be very
火柴盒汽车将会有非常多的
few bugs that's going to hit it okay so
很少有虫子会攻击它 好的
the density is kind of like the density
密度有点像密度
of the world and now that we've made the
现在我们已经取得了世界上
object smaller there's only three
更小的物体只有三个
sprinkles left there's only three bugs
只剩下三个虫子了
that's hit the windshield of our of our
撞到了我们的挡风玻璃上
donut here so this value now needs to be
甜甜圈 所以这个值现在需要为
much bigger in fact it needs to be
事实上 它需要更大的
exactly like if it was 6,000 before it
就像它之前的6000个一样
needs to be yeah 60,000 now um but the
现在需要60,000元 但是
problem is is that it's not just a value
问题是 它不仅仅是一种价值
here the distance Min value has also
这里的最小距离值也有
changed because this is also based on a
更改 因为这也是基于
real world value so this now needs to be
现实世界的价值 所以现在需要
really small so let's try
真的很小 让我们试一试
01 and that's actually pretty good I
01 这实际上是相当好的我
think there's a little bit of over lot
我觉得有一点太多了
but that's roughly kind of what we want
但这大致就是我们想要的
and let's see if I can increase this
让我们看看我能不能增加这个
yeah so if I want this density to be
是的 所以如果我想要这个密度是
really dense yeah I would have to
真的很稠密 是的 我必须
increase it to a crazy number now
现在将其增加到一个疯狂的数字
something I like to do personally this
这是我个人喜欢做的事情
isn't you have to do this but you notice
你不是必须这么做 但是你注意到了吗？
how like this number is really large and
这个数字真的很大
if I want to increase or lower my
如果我想增加或降低我的
sprinkle value and I'm in a different
洒满了价值 我置身于不同的
part of blender if I'm just dragging
搅拌机的一部分 如果我只是拖拽
this value it's having no effect because
该值不起作用 因为
the the range like the scale of it is
它的范围就像它的规模
just so large so what I actually do is I
太大了 所以我真正要做的是
set it to a value that I think makes
将其设置为我认为
sense which in this case is 200 and then
在本例中是200 然后
whatever the value was before it was uh
不管它之前的价值是什么 嗯
200,000 right I do a math value inside
200,000对 我在里面做了一个算术值
of my geometry node setup between here
我的几何体节点设置在这里之间
and here I do a math calculation to
在这里我做了一个数学计算来
multiply that by the value that it needs
将其乘以所需的价值
to be almost as like a scale adjustment
几乎就像比例调整一样
so you can do it with just one node
因此 您只需使用一个节点即可完成
shift a utilities math math and just
转移一个公用事业数学和只是
drop it in here now the math I I said I
现在把它放在这里 我说的数学我
want to multiply it so I need to change
想要成倍增长 所以我需要改变
it from add to a multiply and math is
它从加法到乘法 数学是
the most versatile of any uh node you
你最多才多艺的节点
can do all sorts of stuff but multiply
可以做各种各样的事情 除了乘法
so multiply and it was 200,000 before so
所以乘起来 之前是20万
if I want this value 200 then I just
如果我想要这个值200 那么我就
add uh 1,000 yes that's correct okay so
加1,000 是的 正确 好的 那么
now I can very quickly change the scale
现在我可以非常迅速地改变比例
of the sprinkles across the donut
甜甜圈上的洒水
without having to like manually type in
而不需要手动键入
the value I can just move it back and
我只需要把它移回去 然后
forth um and there you go so that's it
第四 嗯 就是这样 就是这样
so we've uh we've changed the scale of
所以我们 呃 我们已经改变了
it to what it should be um we've got a
它应该是什么样子 嗯 我们有一个
correct uh density sorry we've got a
正确 嗯 密度 对不起 我们有一个
correct sprinkle setup looking good um
正确的洒水设置看起来不错
in the next part we are going to be
在下一部分中 我们将
adding long sprinkles to donut because
在甜甜圈中加入长长的撒料是因为
this round one is okay and I originally
这一轮还可以 我本来
was just going to go round to try and
正准备四处走走试着
keep it simple but there's also I don't
保持简单 但也有我不知道的
know the long sprinkles just look way
我知道长长的散布只需看路
nicer um but you do have to do uh some
更好 嗯 但你确实需要做一些
different rotation math and stuff so
不同的旋转数学和其他东西
we're going to do that in a whole second
我们将在一秒钟内完成这项工作
video so click here on the screen to
视频 因此请点击屏幕上的此处
learn all about that and random colors
学习所有关于那个和随机颜色的知识
so I will see you in that part
所以我会在那部分见到你